Guide to the Roberta Hodes Papers, 1943-1989
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Roberta Hodes Papers
1943-1989
Hodes, Roberta
1.25 cubic feet (2 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Material relating to Hodes’ career in the film industry and her time at Vassar College.
Biographical Note
Vassar, Class of 1946, Editor of the Vassar Miscellany News, script supervisor for a number of Hollywood films.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, photographs, clippings, scrapbooks, scripts, and other material relating to Hodes’ career in the film industry and her time at Vassar College.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Names:
Kazan, Elia
Organizations:
Vassar College--Students; Vassar College--Alumni and alumnae
Subjects:
Women college students--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Women--Film
VCL Categories
Theater, Drama and Film
Encoding Information
Encoded by Adrienne Turner, September 2008.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Roberta Hodes, June 2006
Container List
- Childhood - 1 (1.1)
- Childhood - 2 (1.2)
- Childhood - 3 (1.3)
- Childhood - 4 (1.4)
- Vassar - 1, 1943-1946 (1.5)
- Vassar - 2, 1943-1946 (1.6)
- Vassar - 3, 1943-1946 (1.7)
- Vassar - 4, 1943-1946 (2.1)
- Post Vassar Scrapbook, 1946-1947 (1.8)
- Vassar Later (1.9)
- Misc article on Alumnae Panel, Oct 1971 (2.3)
- Israel - 1, 1946-1950 (1.10)
- Israel - 2, 1946-1950 (1.11)
- Israel - Photos- General (1.12)
- Israel - Photos- Independence Day, 1949 (1.13)
- Double Day - General (1.14)
- Double Day - First Draft of Chapter 1 (1.15)
- "Inhabitants"- Original Clips (1.16)
- "Inhabitants"- AFI (1.17)
- Film Workshop, 1967 (1.18)
- Film Workshop, 1971 or 1972 (1.19)
- Film Proposal - Israel University Film School (1.20)
- Film Proposal - Golda Meir (1.21)
- Film Proposal - "Encounter Films" (1.22)
- Film Proposal - Feminist Film (1.23)
- Film Proposal - 128th Street Mural (1.24)
- Film Proposals - "The Game" Sequel (1.25)
- Manheim Award For "The Game", 1967 (1.26)
- Tours Prize for "The Game", 1968 (1.27)
- NYU Teaching, 1974-1989 (1.28)
- Trial (1.29)
- Writings, A-F (1.30)
- Writings, G (1.31)
- Writings, H-I (1.32)
- Correspondence (1.33)
- Notebook (1.34)
- "Lad: A Dog," Script, 1961 (1.35)
- "Lad: A Dog," Comic Book (1.36)
- "Lad: A Dog," Video Tape (2)
- "A Secret Space," Screenplay, 1975 (1.37)
- "A Street In Harlem," Editing Log (1.38)
- "The Inhabitants," Screenplay, 1965 (1.39)
- DVD - "A Secret Space" (1.40)
- DVD - "The Game" (1.41)
- DVD - "A Street In Harlem" (1.42)
- Scrapbook - Movies, 1952-1983 (1.43)
- Scrapbook - "A Secret Space" (1.44)
- Scrapbook - " The Inhabitants" (1.45)
- Scrapbook - Kazan (2)
- 1964 (2.2)
- Photograph inscribed to Hodes by Samuel Beckett (2.4)
- Photograph of the shooting of "The Magic Garden of Stanley Sweetheart", ca. 1939 (2)